Adam Caplan

Boston, MA * (617) 855-5188 * apcaplan@gmail.com Portfolio: apcaplan.github.io

Software engineer and international yoga teacher with a passion for learning and for helping others to be their best. Over 15 years experience coaching, teaching, problem solving with diverse populations, and creating customized solutions to meet individual needs.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Fellow, General Assembly

Boston, Massachusetts

May 2019 - July 2019

- Completed 12 week, 500+ hour immersive course to hone skills in fullstack responsive web application development
- Built RESTful APIs to integrate data and UI
- Designed and built four single-page web applications with full CRUD actions, implementing mobile-first, responsive design:

> Sun Salutations

- Designed and developed front end React client and back end Rails database of an authenticated application, offering a fun way to learn, practice, and track yoga sun salutations!
- Built full-stack application using React.js, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Material-UI, and RESTful API with Ruby on Rails

> RESTaurant

- Collaborated with three teammates to create a user-friendly app for restaurants to track inventory
- Built using JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, AJAX, Handlebars, Bootstrap, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB
- Developed using SCRUM, other Agile methodologies, team version control
- Completed MVP and project requirements in 3 business days

Mindfulness Meditation Journal

- Designed and developed a full-stack, user-friendly app for journaling meditation experiences, tracking changes, observing progress over time
- Built using JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3/SASS, jQuery, AJAX, Bootstrap, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL
- Cloud-based deployment hosting using GitHub pages and Heroku

Tic Tac Toe

- Developed a two-player SPA game that interacts with a RESTful Rails API to manage user and game data
- Built using JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3/SASS, Bootstrap, and AJAX

Advanced Yoga and Meditation Teacher, Adam Caplan Yoga

Multiple locations in Thailand, India, and USA

October 2005 - present

- Offer workshops, retreats, trainings, and classes in diverse international communities, to over 500 students per year, with classes ranging in size from private one-on-one's to groups of over 100 students
- Assess students' goals and needs, develop individually tailored solutions
- Counsel, teach, train, and mentor yoga teachers

Academic and Test Preparation Coach, PrepMatters

Bethesda, Maryland

August 2003 - August 2007

- Booked over 3,000 hours tutoring students, ages 9-18, in academic subjects and for standardized tests
- Assessed student abilities; designed and implemented individualized plans to meet each student's needs; taught anxiety-relieving techniques
- Developed and implemented curricula for pro-bono student groups

TECHNOLOGY SKILLS

CSS JavaScript React.js HTML Bootstrap **iQuery** SASS Material-Ul Handlebars Rails Node.is Ruby SQL Express.js Mongoose MongoDB Git /GitHub Heroku

EDUCATION

Boston University Boston, MA Bachelor of Arts, English and Religion Magna Cum Laude, University Professors Honors Program

City Year Boston Corps Member

YOGA TEACHER CERTIFICATIONS

Agama Yoga School

Koh Phangan, Thailand Yoga Philosophy and Practice, 2,500+ hours formal study

Hridaya Yoga

Koh Phangan, Thailand (500 hours)

Agama Yoga School

Koh Phangan, Thailand (500 hours)

Kripalu Center

Stockbridge, MA (200 hours)